まさかこんな所に人の住む村があるとは
I can't believe people live here.
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
Yeah, at first glance, it just looks like a mountain.
ね 一見 ただの岩山に見えるもんね
昔戦争から逃れた民が山の中に隠れ住むって物語
イクスが話してたっけ
I think Ik-su mentioned a story about a clan that hid in the mountains to escape the war.
確かるの キジャ
Are you sure, Ki-ja?
はい ここに 青龍が居ます
Yes. The Blue Dragon is here.
Do we have guests?
お客人か
Episode 12:      Blindfolded Dragon
ここの住人...どう出る
How should we approach... these villagers?
ここに青龍を連れてまいれ
Bring the Blue Dragon here!
That's too direct.
直球過ぎだ
Blue Dragon?
青龍
No one by that name lives here.
そのような名の者 ここには居ません
It's not a name. He's a man who possesses a dragon's blood.
名ではない 龍の血を持つ者だ
隠さずともよいから
There's no need to hide him.
このお方がお待ちだと伝えよ
Tell him this person is waiting for him.
何をおっしゃっているのか 分かりませんが
I don't know what you're talking about.
Perhaps you came to the wrong place.
場所を間違えられたのではないですか
This is a small, simple settlement.
ここは何もない小さな集落です
We don't want a lot of commotion.
あまり騒がしくされるのも困るのですが
But...
しかし...
We're sorry.
ごめんなさい
We were traveling in search of someone, but it seems he isn't here.
私達は人を探して旅していたのだけれど
ここではなかったみたい
でも長旅で疲れていてけがしている者も居るの
But we're exhausted from our long journey, and some of us are injured.
I'll humor you
just this once
少し休ませて貰っても
I'll humor you
just this once
Do you think we could...
...rest for a while?
いいかしら
それは難儀でしたな
Your journey must have been difficult.
As you can see, we're poor.
見た通り貧しい集落ですので
We can't offer you anything.
なんのおもてなしもできませんが
構わないわ ありがとう
That's fine. Thank you.
では こちらへ
This way, please.
あの面は
What are those masks?
仕来りなのですよ
They're traditional.
We discourage unmarried villagers from showing their faces to others.
未婚の者はあまり人前で顔をさらすなっと
That's an interesting tradition.
面白いことするのね
As guests, I'm sure you must find it shocking.
お客人からすれば 驚かれる事でしょう
こちらでお休みください
You can rest here.
ありがとう
Thank you.
あぁ お客人
Ah, miss...
ここは迷路のように入り組んでいおります
This place is like a maze.
あまりうろうろならさぬよう
Don't wander around too much.
なにがあっても 責任持ちませんよ
We can't be held responsible for anything that happens to you.
ここって本当に青龍の里なのかな
Is this really the Blue Dragon's village?
どうして
Why do you ask that?
The White Dragon's village was
in awe of your red hair,
白龍の里では
あんなに有難がられたお姫様の赤い髪見ても 反応なしだもん
but these people haven't reacted at all.
Princess, I can feel it.
The Blue Dragon is here.
姫...様 確かに感じるのです ここから青龍を
Don't be silly.
バカね
I don't doubt you, Ki-ja.
キジャを疑ってなんかいないわ
Y-Yes, Princess.
は はい
Idiot.
バカね
Did you call me an idiot?!
バカだと
Either way, we know the Blue Dragon is nearby.
まぁ なんであれ 青龍が近くに居るのは 分かってる訳だ
本人に会わなきゃ始まらない
Until we meet him, we won't get anywhere.
Let's go while there's no one around.
人のいない今のうちに行くよ
That man said this place is a maze.
ここは迷路だって言ってたよ
Will we be all right?
大丈夫
お姫様 俺は天才美少年だよ
Princess, I'm a handsome genius.
こんなとこ ついでに地図作って攻略してやる
I'll make a map as we go
so we can conquer the maze.
Find the treasure!
宝を探せ
Search every pot and drawer you find!
壺と箪笥は片っ端から覗け
Searched
Let's search!
覗くぜ
Searched
Let's search.
Their target is the Blue Dragon
Searched
Conquering the Maze
It's a dead end.
行き止まりだ
Why isn't the Blue Dragon here?
もう なんでいないのさ 青龍
けしからんな なぜ出てこない
This is unthinkable.
Why won't he come out?
私が居ることは分かってるだろうに
He must know I'm here.
あんたが暑苦しいんだろう
You're probably smothering him.
Dodge
Dodge.
Oh, right. The Blue Dragon can sense the White Dragon too, can't he?
あ そっか 青龍にも白龍が分かるんだっけ
あまり出てきたくないのかな
Maybe he doesn't want to come out.
In that case, perhaps we should give up on-
それなら青龍を諦めても...
We can't!
ダメです
Don't give up.
諦めないでください
青龍は私と同じように 長い間 血を繋いできた
Like me, the Blue Dragon comes
from a long line of dragons.
ならば待っているはずです
He must be waiting for you.
自分を必要としてくれる主を 貴方を
For you, a master who needs him.
四龍は本来そのためだけに生まれ
That's why the four dragons were born.
それ以外 なにも望みなどなくて
We desire nothing else.
先代である父も 主を待ち焦がれた
My father, the previous White Dragon,
longed to meet his master.
だが ついに求められる事はなく
However, no one ever sought him out.
青龍も 貴方に会えばきっと
If the Blue Dragon meets you,
I'm sure he will also...
キジャ
Ki-ja?
私は 緋龍王ではないわ
I am not King Hiryuu.
はい...
Right.
でも 貴方だと思ったのです
But I thought it was you.
I'm not King Hiryuu...
緋龍王ではないけど
私は貴方が欲しい
but I want you.
勝手でごめんなさい
Sorry for being so selfish.
Ba-dum
I-I am not worthy.
も もったいないです
雷獣 顔歪んでるよ
Thunder Beast, you're scowling.
ここは なんか嫌な感じ
I have a bad feeling about this place.
What?
なに
誰かが見てる
Someone's watching.
Someone's staring at us with giant eyes.
でっかい目で俺等をじっと見てる
確かに妙な気配が
I do sense a strange presence.
Maybe the residents found us.
ここの住人に見つかったかも
Let's go back.
戻ろうよ
Yes.
Was that a cry?
A passage?
通路
栗鼠
A squirrel.
待って
Wait!
居た
There he is.
He's so cute!
可愛い
Hak, there's an animal-
ハク こんな所に動物...
蝋燭が
The candles...
ハク
Hak!
キジャ
Ki-ja!
Yun!
ユン
どうしよう
What should I do?
Are you lost?
迷われたのですか
Were you separated from your friends?
お仲間とはぐれたのですか
Y-Yes.
Do you live here?
あなたは ここの人
Yes.
はい
Give me your hand.
手を
I will take you to them.
連れて行って差し上げます
Thank you.
ありがとう
ここは迷路だと お聞きには
Weren't you told this place is a maze?
I'm sorry. There's someone I must find.
ごめんなさい どうしても探したい人が居て
青龍...ですか
The Blue Dragon?
Huh? Yes.
There's no such person here.
その様な者は居ません
あの通路の奥は誰かの部屋なの
Does someone live in the room
at the end of that passage?
No one lives there.
誰も居ません
No one.
誰も...
ね そっちはハク達の居る方向じゃないわ
Um, Hak and the others aren't that way.
Why are we going deeper?
なぜ地下に向かうの
放して いや
Let go! No!
Hak! Hak!
ハク ハク
だれ
Who is this?
鈴の音 面をつけてる ここの住人
The sound of bells...
He's wearing a mask.
Does he live here?
でもどうして
But I wonder why...
I'm not afraid.
一つも怖くない
Where are you, Princess?
姫さん どこにいる
Any luck?
そっちは
どこ行っちゃたんだよ
Where did she go?
この気配
This presence...
近い
He's close!
Princess!
姫さん
一体どこに
Where have you been?
バカ ちゃんとついてこいよ バカ
You idiot! You were supposed
to follow us, you nitwit!
Sorry.
ごめんなさい
よかった ご無事で
I'm glad you're safe.
Yes, this man saved...
ええ この者が助けて...
You...
其方
ま 待って
W-Wait!
どうしたの
What is it?
あの者だ
That's him.
He's the Blue Dragon!
あの者が青龍だ
Eighteen Years Ago
生まれたのか 新たな化け物が
Has a new monster been born?
Yes, the child possesses the Blue Dragon's eyes.
あぁ 青龍の目を持つ赤子じゃ
This child will become the next Blue Dragon.
この子が次の青龍様となる
母親はどうした
What happened to the mother?
She killed herself.
自害した
青龍様の世話は誰がするのだ
Who will care for the Blue Dragon?
先代がするだろう
The previous dragon.
それが掟だ
That's the rule.
Now, quickly, the mask...
それより早うお面を
青龍様の力が目覚める前に
before the Blue Dragon's power awakens.
My first memory is of darkness.
最初の記憶は暗闇だった
Four Years Later
Okay, spin! Go!
よし 回れ そうりゃ
いけ
Go, go!
All right!
うっしゃあ
Aw...
Sorry. U-Um...
ごめん あ...あの
見ててもいい
Can I watch?
Blue Dragon!
青龍
Ao...
アオ
こい
Come!
I told you not to go outside
unless you have to!
あまり外に出るなつっただろう
なんで言う事を聞かない
Why didn't you listen to me?!
I'm sorry, Ao.
ごめん アオ
But...
でも
I want friends.
友達 欲しい
それで
So...
Do you think you'll make any friends?!
友達は出来そうかよ
You can't!
無理だろうが
Get that into your head and stay inside!
分かったら家に閉じこもっとけ
ったく面倒ばかりかけやがって
I swear, you're such a handful!
アオ
Ao... Ao.
アオ アオは前の青龍なんだよね
You're the previous Blue Dragon, aren't you?
Why does everyone in the village run from us?
どうして 里の皆 逃げるの
Is my power cursed?
俺の力 呪われてるの
青龍の目を見た者は石になる
Those who see the Blue Dragon's eyes turn to stone.
Huh?
It's a made-up rumor the villagers believe.
って言うのが里の奴等が信じてる出鱈目な噂だ
石にはならないが
You won't turn to stone.
青龍の目の力は見た者の神経を麻痺させる
But the Blue Dragon's eyes paralyze the nerves of those who see them.
場合によっては 心臓までも
It can even paralyze their hearts.
どっちにしても気味悪い力だ
Either way, it's a creepy power.
Don't cry! It's annoying!
泣くな 鬱陶しい
だって俺 やっぱり呪われ...
But I'm really cursed.
Yeah, that's right!
あぁそうだ お前は呪われてんだ 青龍って化け物に
You're cursed by the monster
known as the Blue Dragon!
D-Damn it.
チクショウ 伝説の力か何か知らねぇが
Who gives a damn if it's some legendary power?
Why does it cling to this village?
なんでこの里に付きまとう
Even if the Blue Dragon dies,
a new one is born in this village!
青龍が死んでも
またこの里から生まれてきちまうんだからよ
And the villagers do nothing
but spread stupid rumors!
里の人間はくだらねぇ噂ばかりしやがるし
アオ よくない人が来てる
Ao, bad people are here.
近くか
Are they close?
焚き火囲んでこっちをお見てる
They're standing around a campfire, looking this way.
クソ
Damn it!
アオ
Ao!
Don't help me.
構うな
アオの目は日に日に見えなくなっていた
Ao grew more blind every day.
でも俺の目はアオの力を吸い取るように
But my eyes could see farther and farther,
どんどん遠くまで見えるようになっていた
as though they were absorbing power from Ao's eyes.
That's the village?
あの村か
They say someone with a strange power lives there.
なにか妙な力を持った奴が居るんだぞ
The power of the dragons.
龍の力だそうだ
Yeah, right.
嘘くさい
But it sounds like something nobles would like.
でも高貴な方が好みそうな話だろう
捕えたら高く買ってくれるかも
If we catch him, they might
pay a good price for him.
Oh?
I'm expensive, huh?
俺って高かったのか
Too bad for you, though.
しかし残念だったな
I'm an ordinary swordsman.
I don't use strange powers.
ここに居るのはただの剣士で妙な力など使わない
Threats to my village...
里を脅かす者よ
Your lives were short.
儚い人生だったな
Hope for more in your next lives.
来世に期待しろ
Ao...
アオは
Ao was strong, even though he was blind.
見えなくても強かった
Were you watching my swordsmanship?
俺の剣筋 ちゃんと見てたか
Yes.
Learn to use a sword as quickly as possible.
剣 覚えろよ 一刻も早く
Ao, why do you use a sword?
アオ どうして 剣を使うの
悪い人には目 使わないの
Don't you use your eyes against bad people?
Listen to me, Blue Dragon!
いいか青龍
その眼は呪い目だ
Those eyes carry a curse!
制御の仕方は教えるが 決して使うな
I'll teach you to control them,
but you must never use them!
If you use them, the curse will turn on you.
使えば呪いは自分に返って来る
相手の麻痺は自分の麻痺に
Paralyzing your enemies will paralyze yourself!
両刃の剣なんだよ
It's a double-edged sword!
Even if it weren't, people won't stop hating or coming after you for your power.
そうでなくても こんな力があるから
いつまで経っても 忌み嫌われたり 狙われたり...
Then if I protect the village with a sword
instead of my eyes,
じゃ 目使わないで剣で村 守ったら
can I make friends?
友達 出来る
Of course not.
出来る訳ねぇだろ
アオ
Ao!
待って
Wait!
置いて行かないで
Don't leave me!
アオは剣を教えてくれた
Ao taught me to use a sword.
Ao taught me about the power of my eyes.
アオは目の力の事を教えてくれた
Ao was stern.
アオは厳しかった
Ao grew weaker and weaker.
アオはどんどん弱くなっていた
Ao!
アオ
Damn it...
クソ
消えろ
Get out of here.
アオ
Ao!
Are you okay?
大丈夫
逃げた 逃げたよ アオ
He ran... He ran away, Ao.
Ao?
アオ
I can't see.
見えない
I can't see anything anymore.
もう 何も 見えない
Yes! I can finally die!
やった やっと死ねる
もうなんの力もない
I have no power now!
体も麻痺してやがる
My body is becoming paralyzed!
I have been released!
解放された
俺は 人間だ！
I am human!
あれ
Oh?
お前 鈴なんか持ってたか
Did you always have bells?
I found them.
拾った
音 綺麗だから
They make a pretty sound.
Oh.
いいな それ
That's good.
Even though I can't see you,
I know where you are.
見えなくても お前がどこに居るのか分かる
I'm sorry.
ごめんな
Huh?
I'm sorry...
ごめんな
お前 一人にして
for leaving you alone.
ごめんな
I'm sorry!
Don't, Ao.
嫌だ アオ
もっと別の話 しようよ
Let's talk about something else.
But I'm stupid. I can't think of anything to say.
でも 俺バカだから 言葉何も 浮かばない
You have to talk, Ao.
アオが喋って
Hey, Ao.
ね アオ
Let me hear your voice.
声を聞かせて
先代青龍様が...
The previous Blue Dragon is...
Yes. He's finally dead.
あぁついに
He lasted longer than the others.
しかし長く持った方だ
では 今の青龍様にすべての呪いの力が...
Then the full curse has passed
to the current Blue Dragon.
That's good.
いいな それ
Even though I can't see you,
I know where you are.
見えなくても お前がどこに居るのか分かる
I'm here!
俺は ここに居るよ
何かが来る
Something's coming.
Lots of them. Like soldiers.
沢山 兵士みたいな
あの時逃げた人が兵士に知らせたんだ
The man who ran away must have told the soldiers.
What should I do?
どうしよう 俺の剣じゃまだあんなの倒せない
I'm not strong enough to beat
them with my sword yet.
They'll recognize me easily by my mask.
俺は面をつけてるから すぐに見つかっちゃう
里の秘密がばれたら
If the village's secret gets out...
If they find out, what will happen?
あの人達にばれたら どうなるんだろう
目の力は使うな
You must never use the power of your eyes.
That's right.
そうだ
Everyone fears us and attacks the village
because of this power.
この力があるからみんな怖がって 里は狙われる
It's a curse. A curse.
呪いなんだ 呪い
But...
だけど
Ao protected this village!
この里はアオが守ってきた場所
What... What happened?
な 何が起こったんだ
I'm sorry, Ao.
ごめんね アオ
You were right. This power must never be used.
この力は本当に使ってはいけないものだったんだ
He's the Blue Dragon.
彼が青龍
優しくて
It felt so gentle and warm.
暖かった
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Nod Nod
Next Time
Why do I feel like I've always
wanted to meet this girl?
何故俺はこんなにも
この少女に会いたかったよ思うのだろう
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 13:
次回 暁のヨナ 第十三話
Episode 13:      Echoing Fear
反響する恐怖
Echoing Fear.